University of Arizona Office of the President records, 1937-1947
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
University of Arizona Office of the President records, 1937-1947
AZ 426
Correspondence and financial papers relating to the administration and management of the university including areas such as building and grounds, military matters, student health, land acquisitions, enrollment statistics, student publications, fraternities and sororities, scholarships and awards, WPA Federal Works Agency proposed projects, and other issues.
University of Arizona. Office of the President
20 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None.
Scope and Content Note
Correspondence and financial papers relating to the administration and management of the university including areas such as building and grounds, military matters, student health, land acquisitions, enrollment statistics, student publications, fraternities and sororities, scholarships and awards, WPA Federal Works Agency proposed projects, and other issues. Also includes material concerning World War II including Naval Training School, 1941-1946, the selective service system, and internment of Japanese Americans. Correspondents include U.S. Senators Henry F. Ashurst and Carl Hayden, and U.S. Representative John R. Murdock, Governors R.C. Stanford, Robert T. Jones, and Sidney P. Osborn, and various members of the Board of Regents, faculty and students.
Atkinson, Alfred, 1879-1958; Ashurst, Henry Fountain, 1874-1962 -- Correspondence; Hayden, Carl Trumbull, 1877-1972 -- Correspondence; Murdock, John Robert, 1885-1972 -- Correspondence; Stanford, Rawghlie Clement, 1879-1963 -- Correspondence; Jones, Robert T. (Robert Taylor), 1884- -- Correspondence; Osborn, Sidney Preston, 1884-1948 -- Correspondence; Arizona Board of Regents; Arizona. Legislature; University of Arizona -- Faculty; University of Arizona -- Records and correspondence; University of Arizona -- History; Japanese Americans -- Evacuation and relocation, 1942-1945; World War, 1939-1945 -- United States -- Education and the war; Arizona -- History -- Sources; Correspondence
Additional Atkinson papers at AZ 294; additional President's papers at AZ 76, AZ 406, AZ 420, AZ 427.
Container List
- College of Agriculture: Dean Paul S. Burgess and acting Dean R.S. Hawkins. 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- College of Agriculture: Correspondence with P.S. Burgess in Rhode Island. June 1938-August 1939 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- College of Agriculture: Dean Paul S. Burgess and acting Dean R.S. Hawkins. 1939-1941 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- College of Agriculture: Dean Paul S. Burgess. 1942-1947 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Includes letter of February 5, 1944 from Botany Professor Lyman Benson regarding the history and future development of the Herbarium.
- College of Agriculture: Faculty: George W., Agricultural Economist. 1937-1947 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- College of Agriculture: Faculty: Brown, J.G., Plant Pathology. 1937-1947 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- College of Agriculture: Faculty: Cline, R.W., Agricultural Education. 1937-1947 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- College of Agriculture: Faculty: Smith, G.E.P., Irrigation Engineer. 1937-1947 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- College of Agriculture: Faculty: Stanley, E.B., Animal Husbandy. Includes information about the operation of the UA Farm and its livestock. 1937-1947 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- College of Agriculture: Faculty: Vorhies, Charles T., Entomology and Economic Zoology. 1937-1947 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- College of Agriculture: Faculty: Various and Miscellaneous. 1937-1947 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Includes Davis, R.N., Dairy Husbandry; Embleton, Harry, Poltry Husbandry; Finch, A.H., Horticulture; Smith, H.V., Agricultural Chemisty.
- College of Agriculture: Personnel; Appointments, Salaries, Trips, etc. 1937-1947 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- College of Agriculture: Budget and Financial Records. 1937-1947 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- College of Agriculture: Guayule Research. 1942-1945 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- College of Agriculture: Agriculture classes at Tempe. 1940,1946-1947 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- College of Agriculture: Possiblity of relocating in Phoenix area. 1937-1947 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- College of Agriculture: List of Graduates. 1913-1938 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- College of Agriculture: School of Home Economics. 1937-1947 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Agricultural Experiment Stations: Casa Grande Highway Farm. 1937-1947 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Agricultural Experiment Stations: Mesa Farm. 1937-1947 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Agricultural Experiment Stations: Safford Farm. 1937-1947 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Agricultural Experiment Stations: Salt River Valley Citrus Reseach Farm. 1937-1947 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Agricultural Experiment Stations: Salt River Valley Vegetable Research Farm (formerly Tempe Date Garden). 1937-1947 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Agricultural Experiment Stations: Tucson Farm (Campbell Ave.). 1937-1947 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Agricultural Experiment Stations: Yuma-Mesa Farm (Gila Project, etc.). 1937-1947 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Agriculture Extension Service: Director, Charles U. Pickrell. 1937-1947 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Agriculture Extension Service: Director, Charles U. Pickrell. 1937-1947 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Agriculture Extension Service: Director, Charles U. Pickrell. 1937-1947 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Agriculture Extension Service: Director, Charles U. Pickrell. 1937-1947 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Agriculture Extension Service: Director, Charles U. Pickrell. 1937-1947 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Agricutlure Extension Service: Farm Labor Program (War Food Administration). 1943-1947 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Agricutlure Extension Service: Farm Labor Program (Trailers). 1944-1946 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Agricutlure Extension Service: Staff. 1937-1947 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Agricutlure Extension Service: Home Demonstration Personnel. Includes correspondence regarding need for a African American home demonstration agent in Maricopa County. April 1945-June 1945 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- College of Liberal Arts: Dean E.R. Riesen. Includes correspondence regarding a proposed classroom building, September - October 1938. 1937-1942 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- College of Liberal Arts: Dean E.R. Riesen. Includes correspondence regarding a proposed classroom building, September - October 1938. 1937-1942 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- College of Liberal Arts: Dean E.R. Riesen. Includes correspondence regarding a proposed classroom building, September - October 1938. 1937-1942 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- College of Liberal Arts: Dean E.R. Riesen, Dean Robert L. Nugent. 1943-1944 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- College of Liberal Arts: Dean Robert L. Nugent. 1945-1947 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- College of Liberal Arts: Personnel appointments, salaries, activities, etc. 1937-1947 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- College of Liberal Arts: Personnel appointments, salaries, activities, atc. 1937-1947 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- College of Liberal Arts: Latin American Programs. 1937-1947 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  Includes correspondence with the Coordinaror of Inter-American Affairs regarding lectures and correspondence about the headship of the University's Department of Latin American Cultures, chiefly with Richard Pattee, 1944-1945.
- College of Liberal Arts: Proposed School of Pharmacy. 1946-1947 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- College of Liberal Arts: School of Business and Public Administration, Director E. J. Brown. 1937-1943 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- College of Liberal Arts: School of Business and Public Administration, Faculty. 1937-1947 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- College of Liberal Arts: School of Business and Public Administration, Survey. June 1942 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- College of Liberal Arts: Faculty: Anderson, Earnest, Chemisty. Includes his research for industrial companies. 1942 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- College of Liberal Arts: Faculty: Brooks, John, Spanish. 1937-1947 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- College of Liberal Arts: Faculty: Fitz-Gerald, John D., Spanish. 1937-1947 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- College of Liberal Arts: Faculty: Haury, Emil W., Anthroplogy and Director of the Arizona State Museum. Includes information on Fort Lowell Ruins and the Museum Building. 1937-1947 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- College of Liberal Arts: Faculty: Haury, Emil W., Anthroplogy and Director of the Arizona State Museum. Includes information on Fort Lowell Ruins and the Museum Building. 1937-1947 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- College of Liberal Arts: Faculty: Haury, Emil W., Anthroplogy and Director of the Arizona State Museum. Includes information on Fort Lowell Ruins and the Museum Building. 1937-1947 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- College of Liberal Arts: Faculty: Houghton, Neal D., History and Political Science. 1937-1947 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- College of Liberal Arts: Faculty: Lockwood, Frank C., English. 1937-1947 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- College of Liberal Arts: Faculty: Solve, Melvin T., English. 1937-1947 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- College of Liberal Arts: Faculty: Tucker, William J., English. 1937-1947 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- College of Liberal Arts: Faculty: Warner, Earle H., Physics. 1937-1947 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- College of Liberal Arts: Faculty: Various A-K 1937-1947 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  Includes Bork, A.W., Spanish; Caldwell, G.T., Zoology; Gillmor, Frances, English; Hamilton, Marie, English; Hubbard, H.H., History and Political Science; Kurath, William, German.
- College of Liberal Arts: Faculty: Various L-Z. 1937-1947 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  Includes Muir, A. Laurence, English; Nicholson, Helen, Spanish; O'Connor, Jack, Journalism; Pattison, Sidney F., English; Riesen, Emil R., Philosophy and Psychology; Roy, Francis A., French; Schneck, M.M.R., Philosophy and Psychology; Summers, Richard, English.
- College of Liberal Arts: Faculty: Miscellaneous. 1937-1947 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- College of Business and Public Administration: Dean E. J. Brown. 1943-1947 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- College of Business and Public Administration: Faculty. 1937-1927 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- College of Business and Public Administration: Reports. 1944 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- College of Education: Dean J.W. Clarson, Jr. Includes a brief history of the development of the College in letter of January 8, 1940. 1937-1947 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- College of Education: Dean J.W. Clarson, Jr. Includes a brief history of the development of the College in letter of January 8, 1940. 1937-1947 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- College of Education: Faculty. 1937-1947 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- College of Education: Graduate student problem, Selma Herr. 1938-1945 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- College of Fine Arts: Dean Arthur Olaf Andersen. 1937-1947 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- College of Fine Arts: Dean Arthur Olaf Andersen. 1937-1947 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- College of Fine Arts: Dean Arthur Olaf Andersen. 1937-1947 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  Folders 8-10 include an evaluation of the Art Department by Gerry Peirce, April 1938; proposal for a music festival, 1938-1939; repairs in Herring Hall for use of Drama Department, 1940; accomodations for Marian Anderson at President's House, October 1941; possible acquisition of a painting of an Indian scene in the Yuma U.S. O. Office, created by Italian prisoner of war, 1945-1946.
- College of Fine Arts: Faculty: Cable, W. Arthur, Speech. 1937-1947 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- College of Fine Arts: Faculty: Katherine Kitt, F., Art. 1937-1947 (Box 6, Folder 12)
- College of Fine Arts: Faculty: Wilison, George C., Music. 1937-1947 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- College of Fine Arts: Faculty: Various and Miscellaneous. 1937-1947 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  Includes: Altman, Elenore - Music; Barton, Lucy, Drama; Colcaire, Oscar, Music; Davis, Gordon, Drama; Huyck E. Mary, Speech; Marroney, Peter, Drama; Pease, Rollin, Music; Scott, J. Powell, Art.
- College of Law: Deans S. M Fegtly, J. Byron McCormick. 1937-1939 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- College of Law: Dean J. Byron McCormick. Includes correspondence while acting president, August 1946. 1940-1941 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- College of Law: Dean J. Byron McCormick. Includes correspondence while acting president, August 1946. 1940-1941 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- College of Law: Faculty: Smith, Chester H. 1937-1947 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- College of Law: Faculty: Varioius and Miscellaneous. 1937-1947 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- College of Law: Opinions. Legal advice by the President regarding University problems and affairs. 1938-1947 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- College of Law: Opinions. Legal advice by the President regarding University problems and affairs. 1938-1947 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- College of Mines and Engineering: Arizona Bureau of Mines Dean G.M. Butler. 1937-1940 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- College of Mines and Engineering: Arizona Bureau of Mines Dean G.M. Butler. 1937-1940 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- College of Mines and Engineering: Engineers' Council for professional development. 1937-1939 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- College of Mines and Engineering: List of graduates. 1898-1937 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- College of Engineering: Dean G. M. Butler. 1940-1947 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- College of Engineering: Dean G. M. Butler. 1940-1947 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- College of Engineering: Dean G. M. Butler. 1940-1947 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- College of Engineering: Faculty. 1937-1947 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  Includes Clark, J.C. - Electrical Engineering; Park, John C. - Civil Engineering; Thornburg, M.L. - Mechanical Engineering; Thornburg, P.L. - Mechanical Engineering.
- College of Mines: Arizona Bureau of Mines, Dean T.G. Chapman. 1940-1947 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- College of Mines: Arizona Bureau of Mines, Dean T.G. Chapman. 1940-1947 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- College of Mines: Arizona Bureau of Mines, Dean T.G. Chapman. 1940-1947 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- College of Mines: Arizona Bureau of Mines, Dean T.G. Chapman. 1940-1947 (Box 9, Folder 4)
- College of Mines: Faculty. 1937-1947 (Box 9, Folder 5)
- College of Mines: Building Adjustments and Equipment. 1937-1947 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- College of Mines: Isabella and Black Diamond Mining Claims, Santa Cruz County. 1943-1947 (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Arizona bureau of Mines: George R. Fansett. 1937-1947 (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Arizona bureau of Mines: Ore testing. 1940-1943 (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Graduate College and Committee: Dean T.G. Chapman and Dean Robert L. Nugent. 1937-1940 (Box 9, Folder 10)
- Graduate College and Committee: Dean Robert L. Nugent. 1941-1942 (Box 9, Folder 11)
- Graduate College and Committee: Dean Robert L. Nugent; Dean John F. Walker; Richard A. Harvill. 1943-1947 (Box 9, Folder 12)
- Dean of Women: Evelyn Jones Kirmse. 1937-1941 (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Dean of Women: Evelyn Jones Kirmse. 1937-1941 (Box 10, Folder 2)
- Dean of Women: Emma K. Burgess Herrick, Hazel MacCready. 1942-1947 (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Dean of Women: Accidents and health problems. 1937-1947 (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Dean of Women: Dormitories: Pima Hall, includes material relationg to the rental in 1939 of 819. N. Euclid Ave. 1937-1947 (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Dean of Women: Dormitories: General. 1937-1947 (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Dean of Women: Personnel, includes correspondence regarding nurses in dormitories, 1938-1940. 1937-1947 (Box 10, Folder 7)
- Dean of Women: Soororities. 1937-1947 (Box 10, Folder 8)
- Dean of Women: Miscellaneous Topics. 1937-1947 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  Includes Social Functions and Policies, 1938-1945; scholarships for Women, 1937-1941; Social Fundamentals Cource, 1938-1944; Marching Squad Drill Team, etc., 1939-1940; Evelyn Jones Kirmse Cup, 1947.
- Dean of Women: Evelyn J. Kirmse's correspondence with President Atkinson after leaving the University of Arizona. 1942-1947 (Box 10, Folder 10)
- Dean of Men: Arthur H. Otis and J.L Slonaker. 1937-1946, 1947 (Box 10, Folder 11)
- P.E. for Men: Director J.F. McKale. 1937-1947 (Box 11, Folder 1)
- P.E. for Men: Director J.F. McKale. 1937-1947 (Box 11, Folder 2)
- P.E. for Men: Director J.F. McKale. 1937-1947 (Box 11, Folder 3)
- P.E. for Men: Director J.F. McKale. 1937-1947 (Box 11, Folder 4)
- P.E. for Men: Staff, Includes Casteel, Miles; Landreth, O.M.; Oliver, "Tex"; Picard, J.L.; Zarza, Louis. 1937-1947 (Box 11, Folder 5)
- P.E. for Men: Condition and use of gym, pool, and fields, etc. 1937-1947 (Box 11, Folder 6)
- P.E. for Men: Athletic relations representative: William Kimball. 1939-1940 (Box 11, Folder 7)
- P.E. for Women: Director Ina E. Gittings. 1937-1947 (Box 11, Folder 8)
- P.E. for Women: Director Ina E. Gittings. 1937-1947 (Box 11, Folder 9)
- P.E. for Women: Women's building: use of, adjustments, etc. 1937-1947 (Box 11, Folder 10)
- P.E. for Women: Women's Athletic field. 1937-1947 (Box 11, Folder 11)
- P.E. for Women: Proposed abandonment of the Rhythmics Department. 1938 (Box 11, Folder 12)
- Health Service: Doctors F. P. Perkins, I.E. Huffman, and J.E. Andes. 1937-1940 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  Includes letter of November 28, 1939 from Dr. Andes, proposing a two-year medical school for the UA; and correspondence regarding nurses in dormitories, 1939-1940.
- Health Service: Dr. J.E. Andes. Includes correspondence regarding physical examinations of faculty, chiefly for TB. 1941 (Box 12, Folder 2)
- Health Service: Doctors J.E Andes, I.E. Huffman, and B.B. Edwards. Includes report on the sanitary conditions of fraternities and sororities. 1942-1947 (Box 12, Folder 3)
- Health Service: Dr. J.E. Andes's correspondence with President Atkinson after leaving the University of Arizona. 1943-1947 (Box 12, Folder 4)
- Health Service: Budget and Equipment. 1937-1947 (Box 12, Folder 5)
- Library: Librarian William H. Carlson. 1937-1941 (Box 12, Folder 6)
- Library: Librarians William H. Carlson and Frederick Cromwell. 1942-1947 (Box 12, Folder 7)
- Library: Budget. 1937-1947 (Box 12, Folder 8)
- Library: Building, includes lighting and cooling. 1937-1947 (Box 12, Folder 9)
- Library: "Friends of the Library". 1939-1942 (Box 12, Folder 10)
- Library: War Information Library. 1941-1945 (Box 12, Folder 11)
- Library: Bill Bishop Aeronautical Library and Bond Drive. 1937-1947 (Box 12, Folder 12)
- Library: Faculty bibliography; Estelle Lutrell; William H. Carlson's correspondece with President Atkinson after leaving the University of Arizona. 1942-1945 (Box 12, Folder 13)
- Military Science and Tactics: Cols. A. W. Holderness, T.G. Peyton, and W.F. Falk. 1937-1940 (Box 13, Folder 1)
- Military Science and Tactics: Cols. W.F. Falk, L.G. Gibney, and A.W. Holderness. 1941 (Box 13, Folder 2)
- Military Science and Tactics: Cols. A.W. Holderness and p.B. Shotwell. 1942-1944 (Box 13, Folder 3)
- Military Science and Tactics: Cols. P.B. Shotwell and T.K. Brown. Includes letter from General George Marshall, April 2, 1945. 1945-1947 (Box 13, Folder 4)
- Military Science and Tactics: Calvary Unit and horses. Includes letters from Senator Carl Hayden and other members of Congress. 1937-1947 (Box 13, Folder 5)
- Military Science and Tactics: Grounds, Buildings, and Stables. Includes correspondence regarding the lease of the stables by the Boarder Patrol. 1944-1947 (Box 13, Folder 6)
- Military Science and Tactics: Polo, includes Polo field. 1937-1947 (Box 13, Folder 7)
- Military Science and Tactics: Women's riding class accident. March 17, 1944 (Box 13, Folder 8)
- Military Science and Tactics: Establishment of Air R.O.T.C. Unit. 1946 (Box 13, Folder 9)
- Military Science and Tactics: Compulsory military training. 1937-1947 (Box 13, Folder 10)
- Steward Observatory: Direcrtors A.E. Douglass and E.F. Carpenter. 1937-1947 (Box 13, Folder 11)
- Labortory of Tree-Ring Research: Director A.E. Douglass. 1937-1947 (Box 13, Folder 12)
- Comptroller: J.P. Herndon and Harry T. Healy. 1937-1939 (Box 14, Folder 1)
- Comptroller: Harry T. Healy and John L. Anderson. 1940-1947 (Box 14, Folder 2)
- Comptroller: Harry T. Healy and John L. Anderson. 1940-1947 (Box 14, Folder 3)
- Comptroller: Harry T. Healy on leave during World War II. 1943-1945 (Box 14, Folder 4)
- Comptroller: State Auditor, claims, etc. 1937-1947 (Box 14, Folder 5)
- Comptroller: State Auditor, claims, etc. 1937-1947 (Box 14, Folder 6)
- Comptroller: Nugent travel request. 1941-1942 (Box 14, Folder 7)
- Comptroller: Claim against. 1944-1946 (Box 14, Folder 8)
- Comptroller: Bonds, securities, and investments. 1937-1947 (Box 14, Folder 9)
- Comptroller: Budget. 1937-1947 (Box 14, Folder 10)
- Comptroller: Disposal Authorizations (War time scrap??). 1941-1945 (Box 14, Folder 11)
- Comptroller: Faculty and staff: general. 1937-1947 (Box 14, Folder 12)
- Comptroller: Faculty and Staff: Appointments and resignations. 1937-1947 (Box 14, Folder 13)
- Comptroller: Facutly and Staff: Retirement and Insurance. 1937-1947 (Box 14, Folder 14)
- Comptroller: Gifts and Endowments: Various and Miscellaneous. Includes Florence Pond Lecture Fund and Anita Post Estate. 1937-1947 (Box 15, Folder 1)
- Comptroller: Gifts and Endowments: James Foundation of N.Y., Inc. 1943-1944 (Box 15, Folder 2)
- Comptroller: Insurance. 1937-1947 (Box 15, Folder 3)
- Comptroller: Land and Property: Various. 1940-1946 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  Includes, Poultry Farm (old and new) 1940-1946; Hansberger Property, Yuma County, 1940-1946; Page land, Pinal County, near Oracle, 1940-1941; proposed gift of land near Tucson by Florence Waterbury, 1940-1941; sand area east of Campbell Ave. Bridge, 1941-1942; Fort Lowell Ruins, 1941-1944; Canal Subdivision, Richmond, California, 1942-1945; property in Tucson Mountains, 1944; Dunipace property, Highland Ave. Tucson, 1946.
- Comptroller: Land and Property: Survey of land belonging to UA. 1937-1947 (Box 15, Folder 5)
- Comptroller: Land and Property: Miscellaneous correspondece. 1937-1947 (Box 15, Folder 6)
- Comptroller: Military contracts. 1937-1947 (Box 15, Folder 7)
- Comptroller: Scholarships. 1937-1947 (Box 15, Folder 8)
- Comptroller: Scholarships, Presidents letters to students. 1937-1947 (Box 15, Folder 9)
- Comptroller: Statement of student costs and distribution of expenditures. 1937-1947 (Box 15, Folder 10)
- Comptroller: Travel expenses. 1937-1947 (Box 15, Folder 11)
- Comptroller: Tuition and Fees. 1937-1947 (Box 15, Folder 12)
- Comptroller: Miscellaneous; fraternities and sororities, cameras, typewritters, etc. 1937-1947 (Box 15, Folder 13)
- Comptroller: Residence Department. 1937-1947 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  Includes correspondence regarding the rental and operating costs of Phi Gamma Delta and Sigma Chi fraternity houses as use as women's dormitories, 1943-1945
- Comptroller: Dining Hall. 1937-1947 (Box 15, Folder 15)
- Comptroller: Mailing and Mimeographing Bureau. Includes material relating to the examination theft in Novemeber 1946. 1937-1947 (Box 15, Folder 16)
- Registrar: C. Zaner Lesher. 1937-1947 (Box 16, Folder 1)
- Registrar: Enrollment Statisitics, etc. 1937-1947 (Box 16, Folder 2)
- Registrar: Enrollment Statisitics, etc. 1937-1947 (Box 16, Folder 3)
- Registrar: Teaching loans. 1937-1947 (Box 16, Folder 4)
- Registrar: World War II: Military withdrawls, veterans, etc. 1937-1947 (Box 16, Folder 5)
- Registrar: Various Topics. Includes staff, equipment, student marriages, small enrollments in various classes, individual student problems and requests. 1937-1947 (Box 16, Folder 6)
- University Extension Division: Director Max P. Vosskuhler. 1937-1947 (Box 16, Folder 7)
- University Extension Division: Press Bureau. 1937-1947 (Box 16, Folder 8)
- University Extension Division: Radio Bureau, correspondence with KOY, Phoenix. 1937-1938 (Box 16, Folder 9)
- University Extension Division: Radio Bureau. 1939-1947 (Box 16, Folder 10)
- University Extension Division: Radio Bureau. 1939-1947 (Box 16, Folder 11)
- University Extension Division: Radio Bureau, programs. 1937-1947 (Box 16, Folder 12)
- University Extension Division: Visual Aids. 1937-1947 (Box 16, Folder 13)
- Associated Students Graduate manager: A.L. Sloanaker. 1938-1947 (Box 17, Folder 1)
- Associated Students Graduate manager: Summer editions of the Arizona Wildcat. 1937-1947 (Box 17, Folder 2)
- Bookstore. 1937-1947 (Box 17, Folder 5)
- Allumni Association. 1937-1947 (Box 17, Folder 6)
- Allumni Association. 1937-1947 (Box 17, Folder 7)